RAZA MEHDI

Senior Software Engineer

DETAILS

PHONE 03334708699 **EMAIL** syedrazamehdi1990@gmail.com LINKS LinkedIn **SKILLS** PHP Laravel Ability to Work in a Team JavaScript VueJS Angular Complex Problem Solving **Redis** Leadership Skills

Bootstrap

PROFILE

I am a Senior Software Engineer having more than 7 years of experience in the software industry. I am passionate about quality software development and I am ready to learn anything new and exciting. I care about how much influence the software has on our society and how much is it important that we should develop it carefully.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer, The Hexaa

Lahore

Jun 2021

- · Define and develop guidelines to ensure code quality.
- · Assist developers and engineers in resolving key issues.
- · Work through the identification and resolution of technical issues.
- · Collaborate with teams to deliver advancements and solutions.
- $\cdot \;\;$ Work to build and improve upon tools.
- · Mentor & lead junior developers.

Software Engineer, Abacus Consulting

Lahore

Nov 2020 — Jun 2021

- Developing new features and maintaining old features in an in-house built software solution.
- · Improving the code quality using the best practices.
- · Working in a team and helping my peers to get the job done.

Software Engineer, Shayan Solutions

Lahore

Jun 2018 — Nov 2020

- Remove errors and bugs from a legacy system and add new features to it as well.
- Develop API for some mobile applications which are available on the Apple App Store and Googles Play Store. References are available on request.
- Develop an application using Laravel Nova, Google IoT Core and Google BigQuery that handles the automatic switching of real IoT devices within an organization.

MySql
Laravel Nova
Docker
Laradock
Stripe Integration
PayPal Integration
NodeJs
_

LANGUAGES

English

Urdu

HOBBIES

Reading, Swimming, Table Tennis, Soccer, Cricket

Software Developer, Rocksteady Software (Defunct)

Dec 2016 — Jun 2018

- · Worked as a full-stack developer where I was responsible for writing the business logic and was used to develop the API for an app in Laravel.
- · My other responsibility was to construct the front end of one application using Angular JS and the other application in Angular.
- · Work on some smaller projects which were in Code Igniter or Cake PHP.

Software Developer, Soft Pyramid

Lahore

Lahore

Apr 2015 — Dec 2016

- · My responsibility was to code the business logic for the applications using Laravel. I was using jQuery for handling the front-end manipulation and handling. Integrating the required 3rd party API with the applications was another responsibility.
- · I managed to add the login through Facebook and Gmail and added google maps to a web application with the vendor's details popping up on the map.
- · I successfully integrated payment gateways like Stripe, Sage Pay, and PayPal for three different web applications

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science, Virtual **University of Pakistan**

Lahore

Sep 2009 — May 2015

HSSC, Govt. College of Science, Lahore

Lahore

2006 - 2009

REFERENCES

Arslan Ali

Shayan Solutions

shayansolutions@gmail.com +923004412255